<topics>
	
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-passenger-pigeons/introduction</id>
    
	<results>
		
	      <result>
		<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn87080287/1889-11-28/ed-1/seq-2/</id>
		<rel>0</rel>
	      </result>
      
		<result>
		<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84020558/1908-05-04/ed-1/seq-7/</id>
		<rel>1</rel>
		<text>A PLEA FOR
WILD PIGEONS
For Protection Against
' Wanton Slaughter
A Few Facts Concerning
Their Names and Migrat
ing Habits.
To the Editor of The Republican, sir:
Now that the northern flight of the
wild "doves" and "white winas" has
begun, may I be permitted to offer a
few remarks pertinent to this kind of
game, more particularly in favor of
its protection against complete exter
mination? Having been taught, from
earlv boyhood, to tram; over hill and
dale in cuest if game. I was always
admonished never to bag tnore game
than was actually needed.
Judging from this standpoint you
will readily understand why I take
such interest in this matter. Accord
ing to my method of reasoning the wild
pigeon needs as yiueh protection as the
wild duck, the wild turkey, or deer,
quail, grouse, prairie chicken, etc.
Cannot a law be enacted limiting the
bagging of this kind of game to fifty
birds per day for each person, or some
tiling similar to the law relating to
quail, so that the game butchers may
be prevented from doing such wanton
slaughter? Why not limit the shoot
ing of wild pigeons from April 15th to
August 1.1th, and make the closed sea
son from August 16th of one vear to
April 14th of the next year following?
Likewise preventing the sale or barter
of such came? Let us be true sports
men and not wholesale pot-hunters or
hogs. The practice of hunters killing
from two hundred to six hundred wild
pigeons in one day appears to me to
be unreal and inhuman, tending rather
to encourage others to excel in this
needless killing of birds. This is not
true sport. I call it plain, downright
d.-.-tructiveness. or murder! The fair
minded sportsman satisfies himself
with winging a bountiful number of
birds, and does not shoot for the sake
f seeing how many he can get at one
tand.
I venture to assert that if the whole
sale slaughter of these wild pigeons
oi-tinues so unmercifully for the next
f'-w years as has been done in the past,
;il, bearing in mind that the number
of hunters increases each successive
year in - equal proportion, they will
have become almost extinct within the
next forty to fifty years, or perhaps
e-irliei. and then tilere will be a repe
lion'of e--.o t!y the same conditions as
thry now exist in the central and
astern states, namely, a woeful scare-
ity of these birds, brought about
through utter jieglect in failing to pro
vide for their protection. Let us take
warning from the experiences of our
eastern neighbors. It is a lamentable
fact that the eastern states had but
few game laws previous to the year
1ST6. hence the scarcity of "furs, fins
and feathers" in those sections. Then
let us, while the opportunity presents
itself, protect this feathered tribe. I
call upon that true and gentlemanly
sportsman. Captain Crenshaw, prese
senting the territorial legislature from
this county, to interest himself in be
half of this humane raise.
The lessons taught nie in my youth
have always stood me in good stead.
Only once, however, did 1 break tl
game laws. This incident happened
away up in Aroostook county. Maine,
in November. 1S7S, at a time when
large game in thiit region was decid
edly much more plentiful than it is at
the present time. The laws but then
recently enacted, allowed the killing
of one moose, or deer, per day to each
num. There were five in our party,
including our old friend, guide and
trapper. Joe Murphy, from Kangor,
since deceased, whose fame as a stalk
er was world-wide. It appeared that
the moose all came my way. and 1 des
patched them in their order of appear
ance, since no one in our party had
succeeded in getting within good range
for the desired results. The third an
imal, however, played "possum on me.
While in the act of using my 8-inch
bowie (the 44-inch rifle standing
against a tree some ten feet distant)
the bull moose jumped up between me
and the rifle and charged against me.
My only protection lay in making for
the nearest pine tree. The 'wounded
animal then wedged its antlers against
that tree, finally extricating itself, and
moving hurriedly in the opposite di
rection from that in which it came.
Remember please, that magazine rifles
were not generally in use during those
davs and that the time consumed in
running for that sun and re-loading it
was one of the quickest .acts of my
life. The second attempt., to tip jnv
X-incii bowie proved more successful
than the first. Tr-e hunt on that day
w.is continued until late in the after
noon, when it again became my good
fortune to ,'iiqtroac'i within shooting
range of the fourth animal, which I
brought down by hitting in the upper
left hand shoulder, -penetrating into
the vital region of its heart.. Having
been ignorant of the law relating to
the shooting of moose, I very incau
tiously Informed the game warden that
1 had secured the four moose and was
taken into custody. I was however
Immediately released upon my own
recognizance and through the inter
vention of legal and official friends,
by the payment of a nominal tine, and
returned homeward bound. Our guide.
Murphy, knew the law and had intend
ed asking me to divide up the game
equally among our party, thus avoid
ing detection, but the game warden
arrived in our midst before he had
that opportunity. We were a'owed to
take the game. Kver since that occur
rence I have always faithfully observed
and respected the game laws of the
localities in which I hunted.
It is scarcely needless to state that
I am and always shall be. in favor of
protecting our wild game to the fullest
extent of the law.
Why the local hunters persist in call
ing these birds wild "doves" or "white
wings" is beyond the ken of the ornith
ologist. . They are called passenger
pigeons (ectopistes migratorious of the
family Columbidae) or wild pigeon.
There are upward of three hundred
birds of this order that are listed, but
only twelve species are found in North
America. The wild pigeon migrates
north from Brazil and Central Ameri
ca to Montana, Washington and Ore
gon, or thereabouts, and thence south
ward again to near the equator, with
the seasons, always following the
warn zones. It breeds late in, the win
ter or early in spring, in far osuthern
latitudes, . and w hen the young are
strong enough for distant flight, the
litigatory Instinct asserts Itself late in
March and early in April, preserving
the In migrations northward in large
numbers, feeding all the while, until
late in August, when the southern
flight begins. They do not remain
long in one place when returning.
There are also a few stragglers that
remain in this 'latitude during the
winter .'norths.
The wild pigeon is about twelve to
fourteen inches in length. The male
has upper parts bluish slate, shaded
with olive gray on its back and shoul
ders, metallic violet, gold and green
ish reflections on the back and sides
of its head. The wing covets with vel
vety black spots, throat bluish slate,
quickly shading into a rich reddish
buff on breast, and paling into white
underneath; the middle tail feathers
are black, fading from pearlish into
white. Th" female possesses the Maine
characteristics, except that the upper
parts are washed with more olive
brown: has less frrcdeseence; breast
pale grayish brown fading to white
underneath. The "white wing" of the
family Columbidae bears a striking re
semblance to the male members of
ectopistes, although of a slightly dif
ferent species. It is a male bird, hav
ing a baud of white along its tail
feathers and several white feathers in
its wings, hence the term "white
wings." It is a larger bird than those
previously described, and appears
little later in the season ill this lati
tude than the others.
A noted ornithologist has truly said:
"Vhe modern mind, accustomed to deal
ty with pitfiTrf-reinnarrrs of feathered
races can scarcely grasp the vast num
bers of these birds that once made our
land the sportsman'-s paradise. Unlim
ited' netting has resulted in sending
over one million pigeons to market
from a, single roost in one year, leaving
perhaps as many more wounded birds
and starving almost helpless squabs
behind, until the poultry stalls became
so glutted with pigeons that the low
price per barrel scarcely paid for their
transportation, and they were fed to
the hogs. This abominable practice of
netting and promiscuous killing of
wild pigeons discontinued only because
there were no other flocks left to cap
ture or It:!!, and the few remaining
birds were driven to farther southerly
latitudes to change their habits and
live chiefly in couples. The extermin
ation of the passenger pigeon has pro
gressed so rapidly that it has become
as scarce as the great auk along the
coasts."
There is a vast difference between the
passenger pigeon and the small mourn
ing dove (zenaidura niacroura) seen
in this latitude from March to Novem
ber. The band-tailed or whilecollared
pigeon (Columba fasciata) is mostly
confined to the mountainous regions,
when acorns are abundant. It is of
the same size as the domestic pigeon.
  </text>
      </result>
		
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn86086633/1910-12-08/ed-1/seq-5/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>MILLIONS ONCE:
ONLY 01 NOW
ONLY ONE LIVING PASSENGER
PIGEON. COPPER COUNTRY
HAD MANY IN EAR.
LY DAYS.
One solitary passenger pigeon, end
ing her life ut the Zoological tardea in
Cincinnati, is to-day all that remains
of un American species that early in
the last century swarmed over the con
tinent In Hocks numbering billions.
With the death of this sole survivor
of a bird trloe, whose nesting places
often covered hundreds of square
miles, there will soon disappear the
last trace of the wild pigeons that
huve been slaughtered by the million
by men who fed their hogs upon the
carcasses they could not earry away.
Though It Is too late to save this
species, special efforts are now being
made by the Audubon workers to
bring about the restoration of other
birds of economic value that must
otherwise share the same fate.
At one time passenger pigeons were
prolific in the copper country, espe
cially In the South Range district,
where thousands of them were killed
every season.
Can't Find a Bird.
For many months systematic search
has been made throughout the con
tinent by officials of the Audubon as
sociation for relics of the once prolific
Passenger Pigeon. Members of the
organization headed by professor C
F. Hodge of Clark university have
made a standing offer of $l.f,oo to any
one discovering a nest of this species;
but, though thousands have been try
ing eagerly for the prize, not one sin
gle claimant has appeared. In response
to a recent inquiry by T. Gilbert Pear
son, secretary of the National Associa
tion of Audubon Societies, the author
ities of the Cincinnati Zoo have Just
furnished the last chapter in the tragic
tale of these butchered birds. . The
"Last of the Passenger Pigeons" Is
n female, 18 years old, whose mate
died recently without issue at the age
of 24.
As late as 1877 what is now known
to have been the last nesting place of
these wild birds was found In Mlchl
gan, where their nests thickly cover
ed the trees over an area 28 mile
long and 4 miles wide. Residents of
New York declare that in 1S".0 they
Hocked over Manhattan Island in such
numbers that they obscured the sun
nnd that ships loaded In bulk with the
bodies of these birds lay at the
wharves selling them at a cent apiece.
Audubons is quoted as observing a
roosting place of w ild pigeons In Ken
tucky early In the last 'century that
extended 40 miles and was 3 miles in
width. On its edges, men with guns,
nets, clubs anrt torcl slaughtered the
risisting birds, each often bagging f.oo
in one day. When the wholesale
butchers could carry away no more,
they let .loose droves of hogs to fatten
on what was left. About 1N" this
treatment began to thin the ranks' of
tho passenger pigeons, till two years
ago It was discovered that only seven
could be found on the whole conti
nent, four it Milwaukee and three in
Cincinnati.
Other Birds May be Saved.
Declaring that practically all the
gulls nnd terns in America today have
survived solely through the work of
protection nnd restoration at their
reservations, leaders of the National
Association of Audubon Societies are
now appealing to the people of this
country to support the work of pre
serving dying species of native birds
which they have already begun. The
Upland Plover, Cabot's Tern nnd the
Least Tern, they assert, can now be
saved to the nation by quick emer
gency measures for which special
funds are to be raised. The work of
restoring the Wood Duck and other
game birds that are threatened with
the fate of the Passenger Pigeon is to
be undertaken by the Audubon work
ers with the support of the sportsmen
of the country. Sad as is the passing
of the Passenger Tlgeon, its lesson
may avert the extinction of other val
uable species, it Is declared, If the
American people rally nt once to save
their remaining bird resources.
</text>
      </result>
		
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1913-02-21/ed-1/seq-10/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
THE PASSEN
I
By Frederic
The recent sickness of (lie passenger
pigeon in the Cinelnnai Zoological hardens?the
last survivor of a mighty host?
has served to call the attention of naturalists
again to one of the most remark|
able of all tlie stories of nature's library
?the extinction of one of the most remarkable
birds that ever inhabited the
earth. Millions of people are still living
whose eyes have witnessed the flight of
the myriad hosts of passenger pigeons,
and yet only one of all the vast numbers
of those pigeons is known to survive?
and that one occupies a place of honor
in the Cincinnati Zoo. When he dies it
is probable his body will be presented to
the nation, to be preserved in alcohol at
the National Museum.
In these days it is hard for the younger
people to believe tlie story of the passenger
pigeon, so incredible were their
numbers, so remarkable were their flights
and so strange were their nestings. And
the story of tiie brutality that marked
the work of the pot hunters who followed
them as a tiger stalks ids prey, relentlessly
pursuing them, using the telegraph
to keep in touch with their flights and
their nestings, is a story of revolting
cruelty and butchery.
The world is indebted to John James
| Audubon, the great naturalist, for what
is perhaps the best account of the passenger
pigeon ever written. And his
truthfulness and scientific accuracy made
it a story to be accepted at its face value.
He relates that in the autumn of iHl.'i he
left his house at Henderson, on the banks
of the Ohio, to go to Louisville.
* *
In passing over tlie Barrens, a few
miles front Hardensburg, he observed
pigeons llyCame
Like a Torrent, in? fr?m
, the northWith
Roar of Thunder. east tu lhe
sou tit west in greater numbers than he.
had ever seen before. After they had
been passing for about an hour lie dismounted,
seated himself on an eminence
and made a dot with a pencil for every
Hock that pussea. in a snun. mi?c ? *= j
found that ho was putting down dots at i
the rate of 163 In twenty-one minutes.
He resumed his journey and still the
pigeons came; the light of day was darkened
as if by a solar eclipse. IJke a torrent,
and with the roar of distant thunder,
they gathered in a solid mass, darting
forward with the wings of the wind
in undulating and angular lines, descending
and sweeping close to the earth, then
mounting perpendicularly so as to resemble
a vast column, and when high in
the air once more, wheeling and twisting
within their continued lines, which then
resembled the coils of a gigantic serpent.
For hity-flve miles Audubon traveled on
to Louisville, with the serried columns of |
pigeons still floating over his head, and
for three days the flight continued. Bach
flock did exactly as the one ahead had
done; If the one ahead darted down when
passing over a brook or dodging a hawk
the flock behind did the same. Audubon
attempted to estimate the number of
pigeons in that great flight. lie assumed
that the column averaged a mile in width,
which was far below the average in point
of fact. Then he assumed that the birds
flew at the rate of sixty miles an hour,
also a conservative assumption. Upon
this basis the pigeons passing in three
hours wotild form a streak 180 square i
miles in area, and, counting two pigeons !
to the square yard, there would he nearly |
a billion and a quarter pigeons in such a
flight. How many there must have been
In the three days' flight he did not undertake
to say. Audubon's observations were
that each pigeon eats fully half a pint
of food a day. Tlie pigeons in a threehour
flight would thus need nearly nine
million bushels of food a day.
*
* *
Audubon made several pilgrimages to
a famous roosting place on the banks
of the
Made Several Pilgrimages ? r e e n
to Famous Boosting Place.
tucky. He rode through the forest for
upward of forty miles, and by crossing
and recrosslng it reached the conclusion
that the roost was of an average breadth
of three mileB. His first view of it was
about two weeks after the pigeons had
established it as a roosting place. He
arrived about two hours before sunset
I7V.U7 nlmnnn tvoro tr> ho aoen hilt thero '
" I
were great numbers of people, who, with
horses and wagons, children and dogs,
guns and ammunition, had established
camps on the borders of the forest. Two
farmers had driven more than three hundred
hogs over a hundred miles to fatten
them on pigeons that were to be slaughtered.
Here and there were people engaged
in plucking and salting the catch ;
of the day before. Many trees two feet
in diameter had been broken off by the
sheer weight of the multitudes of roosting
birds. Everywhere great branches of
forest monarchs were broken off, and
the aspect of the thousands of acres of
woodland was such as one might expect
to be the result of a fierce tornado.
Some of the people who were camping
there had great pots of sulphur. Others
had poles, and others guns. It was
after sundown that the cry went up that
the returning hordes were approaching.
The noise they made reminded Audubon
of a gale at ^ea passing through the rigging
of a close-reefed vessel. As they
passed over his head he felt a current of
air that astonished him. Thousands of
birds were knocked down by the polemen.
but tens of thousands and even millions
continued to pour in. They alighted
everywhere, one above another, until
masses as large as hogsheads were
formed on tlie brandies all around.
*
* *
Here and there perches gave way under
the weight with a crash, killing hundreds
of birds
Hundreds of Birds Killed as tllcy
When the Branches Break.
tldng was uproar and confusion. The
people could not hear themselves talking
to one another, ami even the reports of
shotguns and blunderbusses could not be
1 heard above the great noise. Audubon
t a man out from the forest to see
w far the noise could be heard, and it
. is plainly audible three miles distant,
i". midnight the stream of arrivals began
to fall off, hut before the break of day
the advance guard began to move out
U'l.ilft in, dared ne in the
?*?) *! >. ? ? w
woods while the pigeons wore In the
trees, they were able to kill ami eripple
enough of theni to keep all the people
busily employed next day, with enough
left over to give the htm hogs, the wolves,
the foxes, the lynxes, the cougars, bears,
raccoons, possums, polecats, eagles and
hawks a mor>- than satisfactory breakfast.
and at the same time to sa\e enough
back for the vultures that came to supplant
the animals and the birds of prey.
James Fenltnore Cooper also saw the
flights of the passenger pigeons, and lie
said thai, in a single flight he had seen
enough birds to provision Xerxes' army
for a month and enough feathers to provide
a downy couch for every person in
the country.
The white man and his net are responsible
for the disappearance of the
passenger pigeon from the face of the
earth. They began their forays about
1H4<i. The profession of plgeoner came
into existence ami these men banded
themselves together to exploit the pigeon.
*
* *
By the telegraph they were able to
keep in close touch with the movements
of the
Used Telegraph to Keep pigeons.
\I7itb and no
44* A V UUiA VViVU ilAVVVliiVliti). .
pigeon
roost could be established for many days
before the pigeoners were on hund to
get in their deadly work. They carried
with them trained stool pigeons by which
they were enabled to rail down great
flocks of passing birds and net as many
GERPIGEON.
J. Haskin.
as tlicv possibly could park in ire and
ship. In the last great "roosting" in
Michigan in 1S7N more than ">00 tons of
tlie dressed birds were shipped out. Tens
of thousands of them were caught alive
and sold to sporting clubs for trap shooting
purposes.
o ncn some pigeoner nappeneu 10 mscover
that during the nesting season
the birds were frantic In their efforts to
ohtain salty mud and water he found a
bonanza for his ilk. Great mud beds
along streams were covered with salt
and nets were set above these. Hundreds
of thousands of parent birds would
come for their salt and water, the traps
would he sprung, and often a single net
would catch more than a thousand birds.
The pigeoners carried blacksmith pincers,
and a pinch for each captive neck, and
then a struggle, and then some starving
squabs, was the tragedy of their bloody
work.
Chief Pokagon. the last of the Pottav.attomio
chieftains of the Pokagon
band of Indians, says lie saw the pigeoners
in Penzie county. Mich., apply the
match to the mosslike dried bark of the
white birch, which burns like paper soaked
in oil, so that the flame would reach
ttie nests of the pigeons and force the
squabs to jump out. In thousands of instances
the squabs were singed alive and
the parent birds themselves had their
plumage burned badly?some so badly
that they could no longer fly.
*
* *
The pigeon butchers of yesterday were
ready with their defense when needed.
They
Pigeon Butchers Ready p ointed
With Defense of Methods. ti'uto ^ s
and the cattle and the sheep that must
be slaughtered to feed mankind. They
asserted that the pigeons were destructive.
In their own eyes they -were an
ill-used lot. Did not some one tell a
story of poisoning birds with poison
berrier. and cause the price to drop 50
cents a dozen in a single day in New
York, and to IX) cents a dozen in
Chicago? Wasn't killing pigeons with
pincers as humane as shooting quail on
the wing? The stories of great slaughttr
were, to their minds, gross exaggerations.
It has been claimed that there were
flights of passenger pigeons along the
Hudson in ItMi. and John Burroughs investigated
the report and believed It true.
A number of persons have claimed to
have small flocks of the pigeons. In 19<K?
<_*. O. Whitman of the University of Chicago,
reported to W. B. Mershon, author
of "The Passenger Pigeon," that he
had two female birds and two sterile hybrid
males.
But the passenger pigeon is gone from
the earth forever. iDike the great auk
and the buffalo it has been unable to adjust
Itself to the age of the white man
In America.
</text>
      </result>
		
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84024055/1915-05-08/ed-1/seq-8/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>THE PASSENGER PIGEON.
A Beautiful and Useful Bird That U
Now Extinct.
There are men still alive who have
shot not dozens, but hundreds, of pas
senger pigeons In a single day. Sixty
years ago this bird-was far more com
mon In the United States than wild
ducks arc today.
When It migrated the flights dark
ened the sky. A single flight has been
estimated to number over 'iOOO.OOO of
birds.
A. ter weeks ago .the last passenger
pigeon died In Chicago at the age of
twenty-seven years.
A passenger pigeon Is quite a differ
ent looking bird from any.otbcr kind of
pigeon. It has a long tall and is in all
nearly three-quarters of a yard long.
It is so called because of Its migratory
habits. It being a bird of passage.
For the past fifteen years there had
been a standing reward of 51,000 for a
mate for this last survival of her race.
This was several times Its weight in
gold, yet the offer produced no re
sponse. The passenger pigeon is abso
lutely extinct, and one of the most
beautiful and useful of birds has been
wiped out. as it were, under our very
eyes. New York Press.
</text>
      </result>
		
	<result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn86088651/1915-06-22/ed-1/seq-2/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>NO REWARD FOR PAS
SENGER PIGEONS.
Office Of Information, United Statea
Department of Agriculture.
Washington. D. C, June 22.i-Re-fent
widespread newspaper accounts
to the effect that the United States De
partment of Agriculture Is offering
tlO.000 reward to the person find'ng
a psM-nger cr "wood" pigeon test
rnii o
containing two eggs, resulted in hun
dreds of letters being sent to the de
partment. The report la not based
upon facta aa the department baa ot
tered no such reward, and there Is
every i reason to believe tha passen
ger pigeon which formerly roamed
the country In flocks of millions Is
extinct. In 1910 about $1.00.) In re
wards were offered by Clark Univer
sity for tha first undisturbed nests
of the passenger pigeon to be found
In the United States, This waa a
great stimulus to action. The hunt for
this pigeon waa fruitless. The offer
ot rewards was renewed for several
years until It was fully established
that the pigeon waa extinct
. The passenger pigeon up to 1S8J
ranged the American continent east
of the Rocky Mountains. The mourn
ing dove baa often been mistaken for
the passenger pigeon, which in a gen
eral way it resembles. However, this
bird Is quite distinct from the passen
ger pigeon; it Is shorter and hss dif
ferent color markings.
Tbe press reorts stated that the
now extinct passenger plgon was vsK
ued because cf its usefulness In de
stroying the gipsy moth and other
moths and pests which are doing mil
lions of dollars of damage. Although
the preservation of this pigeon l
much to be desired. It would be of ab
solutely no value In eliminating the
gipsy moth as the pigeons are slniot
entirely vegetarian In their diet.

</text>
      </result>

	<result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82015761/1916-06-22/ed-1/seq-5/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Passenger Pigeon Not Extinct
The passenger pigeon . which 50
years ago was th most numerous
game bird on the continent, ' is not
extinct as has. been supposed. . The
destruction of these birds for com
mercial purposes was enormous.
yet to some unknown agency must
be attributed the sudden disappear
ance of the enormous flock which
made their annual passage from
their summer quarters in the far
north to their winter home in the
south.
Quite recently sportsmen have
noticed a few of these birds in the
Santa Fe Canyon of New Mexico.
The birds are well protected by
law and it is hoped that thru such
protection and - the protection
which game protective associations
vill give them these birds may
multiply and again become numerous.
</text>
      </result>

		
    </results>
  </topic>
	
  <topic>
    <id></id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id></id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
