<topics>
	
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-passenger-pigeons/introduction</id>
    
	<results>
		
	      <result>
		<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn87080287/1889-11-28/ed-1/seq-2/</id>
		<rel>0</rel>
	      </result>
      
		<result>
		<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84020558/1908-05-04/ed-1/seq-7/</id>
		<rel>1</rel>
		<text>A PLEA FOR
WILD PIGEONS
For Protection Against
' Wanton Slaughter
A Few Facts Concerning
Their Names and Migrat
ing Habits.
To the Editor of The Republican, sir:
Now that the northern flight of the
wild "doves" and "white winas" has
begun, may I be permitted to offer a
few remarks pertinent to this kind of
game, more particularly in favor of
its protection against complete exter
mination? Having been taught, from
earlv boyhood, to tram; over hill and
dale in cuest if game. I was always
admonished never to bag tnore game
than was actually needed.
Judging from this standpoint you
will readily understand why I take
such interest in this matter. Accord
ing to my method of reasoning the wild
pigeon needs as yiueh protection as the
wild duck, the wild turkey, or deer,
quail, grouse, prairie chicken, etc.
Cannot a law be enacted limiting the
bagging of this kind of game to fifty
birds per day for each person, or some
tiling similar to the law relating to
quail, so that the game butchers may
be prevented from doing such wanton
slaughter? Why not limit the shoot
ing of wild pigeons from April 15th to
August 1.1th, and make the closed sea
son from August 16th of one vear to
April 14th of the next year following?
Likewise preventing the sale or barter
of such came? Let us be true sports
men and not wholesale pot-hunters or
hogs. The practice of hunters killing
from two hundred to six hundred wild
pigeons in one day appears to me to
be unreal and inhuman, tending rather
to encourage others to excel in this
needless killing of birds. This is not
true sport. I call it plain, downright
d.-.-tructiveness. or murder! The fair
minded sportsman satisfies himself
with winging a bountiful number of
birds, and does not shoot for the sake
f seeing how many he can get at one
tand.
I venture to assert that if the whole
sale slaughter of these wild pigeons
oi-tinues so unmercifully for the next
f'-w years as has been done in the past,
;il, bearing in mind that the number
of hunters increases each successive
year in - equal proportion, they will
have become almost extinct within the
next forty to fifty years, or perhaps
e-irliei. and then tilere will be a repe
lion'of e--.o t!y the same conditions as
thry now exist in the central and
astern states, namely, a woeful scare-
ity of these birds, brought about
through utter jieglect in failing to pro
vide for their protection. Let us take
warning from the experiences of our
eastern neighbors. It is a lamentable
fact that the eastern states had but
few game laws previous to the year
1ST6. hence the scarcity of "furs, fins
and feathers" in those sections. Then
let us, while the opportunity presents
itself, protect this feathered tribe. I
call upon that true and gentlemanly
sportsman. Captain Crenshaw, prese
senting the territorial legislature from
this county, to interest himself in be
half of this humane raise.
The lessons taught nie in my youth
have always stood me in good stead.
Only once, however, did 1 break tl
game laws. This incident happened
away up in Aroostook county. Maine,
in November. 1S7S, at a time when
large game in thiit region was decid
edly much more plentiful than it is at
the present time. The laws but then
recently enacted, allowed the killing
of one moose, or deer, per day to each
num. There were five in our party,
including our old friend, guide and
trapper. Joe Murphy, from Kangor,
since deceased, whose fame as a stalk
er was world-wide. It appeared that
the moose all came my way. and 1 des
patched them in their order of appear
ance, since no one in our party had
succeeded in getting within good range
for the desired results. The third an
imal, however, played "possum on me.
While in the act of using my 8-inch
bowie (the 44-inch rifle standing
against a tree some ten feet distant)
the bull moose jumped up between me
and the rifle and charged against me.
My only protection lay in making for
the nearest pine tree. The 'wounded
animal then wedged its antlers against
that tree, finally extricating itself, and
moving hurriedly in the opposite di
rection from that in which it came.
Remember please, that magazine rifles
were not generally in use during those
davs and that the time consumed in
running for that sun and re-loading it
was one of the quickest .acts of my
life. The second attempt., to tip jnv
X-incii bowie proved more successful
than the first. Tr-e hunt on that day
w.is continued until late in the after
noon, when it again became my good
fortune to ,'iiqtroac'i within shooting
range of the fourth animal, which I
brought down by hitting in the upper
left hand shoulder, -penetrating into
the vital region of its heart.. Having
been ignorant of the law relating to
the shooting of moose, I very incau
tiously Informed the game warden that
1 had secured the four moose and was
taken into custody. I was however
Immediately released upon my own
recognizance and through the inter
vention of legal and official friends,
by the payment of a nominal tine, and
returned homeward bound. Our guide.
Murphy, knew the law and had intend
ed asking me to divide up the game
equally among our party, thus avoid
ing detection, but the game warden
arrived in our midst before he had
that opportunity. We were a'owed to
take the game. Kver since that occur
rence I have always faithfully observed
and respected the game laws of the
localities in which I hunted.
It is scarcely needless to state that
I am and always shall be. in favor of
protecting our wild game to the fullest
extent of the law.
Why the local hunters persist in call
ing these birds wild "doves" or "white
wings" is beyond the ken of the ornith
ologist. . They are called passenger
pigeons (ectopistes migratorious of the
family Columbidae) or wild pigeon.
There are upward of three hundred
birds of this order that are listed, but
only twelve species are found in North
America. The wild pigeon migrates
north from Brazil and Central Ameri
ca to Montana, Washington and Ore
gon, or thereabouts, and thence south
ward again to near the equator, with
the seasons, always following the
warn zones. It breeds late in, the win
ter or early in spring, in far osuthern
latitudes, . and w hen the young are
strong enough for distant flight, the
litigatory Instinct asserts Itself late in
March and early in April, preserving
the In migrations northward in large
numbers, feeding all the while, until
late in August, when the southern
flight begins. They do not remain
long in one place when returning.
There are also a few stragglers that
remain in this 'latitude during the
winter .'norths.
The wild pigeon is about twelve to
fourteen inches in length. The male
has upper parts bluish slate, shaded
with olive gray on its back and shoul
ders, metallic violet, gold and green
ish reflections on the back and sides
of its head. The wing covets with vel
vety black spots, throat bluish slate,
quickly shading into a rich reddish
buff on breast, and paling into white
underneath; the middle tail feathers
are black, fading from pearlish into
white. Th" female possesses the Maine
characteristics, except that the upper
parts are washed with more olive
brown: has less frrcdeseence; breast
pale grayish brown fading to white
underneath. The "white wing" of the
family Columbidae bears a striking re
semblance to the male members of
ectopistes, although of a slightly dif
ferent species. It is a male bird, hav
ing a baud of white along its tail
feathers and several white feathers in
its wings, hence the term "white
wings." It is a larger bird than those
previously described, and appears
little later in the season ill this lati
tude than the others.
A noted ornithologist has truly said:
"Vhe modern mind, accustomed to deal
ty with pitfiTrf-reinnarrrs of feathered
races can scarcely grasp the vast num
bers of these birds that once made our
land the sportsman'-s paradise. Unlim
ited' netting has resulted in sending
over one million pigeons to market
from a, single roost in one year, leaving
perhaps as many more wounded birds
and starving almost helpless squabs
behind, until the poultry stalls became
so glutted with pigeons that the low
price per barrel scarcely paid for their
transportation, and they were fed to
the hogs. This abominable practice of
netting and promiscuous killing of
wild pigeons discontinued only because
there were no other flocks left to cap
ture or It:!!, and the few remaining
birds were driven to farther southerly
latitudes to change their habits and
live chiefly in couples. The extermin
ation of the passenger pigeon has pro
gressed so rapidly that it has become
as scarce as the great auk along the
coasts."
There is a vast difference between the
passenger pigeon and the small mourn
ing dove (zenaidura niacroura) seen
in this latitude from March to Novem
ber. The band-tailed or whilecollared
pigeon (Columba fasciata) is mostly
confined to the mountainous regions,
when acorns are abundant. It is of
the same size as the domestic pigeon.
  </text>
      </result>
		
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn86086633/1910-12-08/ed-1/seq-5/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>MILLIONS ONCE:
ONLY 01 NOW
ONLY ONE LIVING PASSENGER
PIGEON. COPPER COUNTRY
HAD MANY IN EAR.
LY DAYS.
One solitary passenger pigeon, end
ing her life ut the Zoological tardea in
Cincinnati, is to-day all that remains
of un American species that early in
the last century swarmed over the con
tinent In Hocks numbering billions.
With the death of this sole survivor
of a bird trloe, whose nesting places
often covered hundreds of square
miles, there will soon disappear the
last trace of the wild pigeons that
huve been slaughtered by the million
by men who fed their hogs upon the
carcasses they could not earry away.
Though It Is too late to save this
species, special efforts are now being
made by the Audubon workers to
bring about the restoration of other
birds of economic value that must
otherwise share the same fate.
At one time passenger pigeons were
prolific in the copper country, espe
cially In the South Range district,
where thousands of them were killed
every season.
Can't Find a Bird.
For many months systematic search
has been made throughout the con
tinent by officials of the Audubon as
sociation for relics of the once prolific
Passenger Pigeon. Members of the
organization headed by professor C
F. Hodge of Clark university have
made a standing offer of $l.f,oo to any
one discovering a nest of this species;
but, though thousands have been try
ing eagerly for the prize, not one sin
gle claimant has appeared. In response
to a recent inquiry by T. Gilbert Pear
son, secretary of the National Associa
tion of Audubon Societies, the author
ities of the Cincinnati Zoo have Just
furnished the last chapter in the tragic
tale of these butchered birds. . The
"Last of the Passenger Pigeons" Is
n female, 18 years old, whose mate
died recently without issue at the age
of 24.
As late as 1877 what is now known
to have been the last nesting place of
these wild birds was found In Mlchl
gan, where their nests thickly cover
ed the trees over an area 28 mile
long and 4 miles wide. Residents of
New York declare that in 1S".0 they
Hocked over Manhattan Island in such
numbers that they obscured the sun
nnd that ships loaded In bulk with the
bodies of these birds lay at the
wharves selling them at a cent apiece.
Audubons is quoted as observing a
roosting place of w ild pigeons In Ken
tucky early In the last 'century that
extended 40 miles and was 3 miles in
width. On its edges, men with guns,
nets, clubs anrt torcl slaughtered the
risisting birds, each often bagging f.oo
in one day. When the wholesale
butchers could carry away no more,
they let .loose droves of hogs to fatten
on what was left. About 1N" this
treatment began to thin the ranks' of
tho passenger pigeons, till two years
ago It was discovered that only seven
could be found on the whole conti
nent, four it Milwaukee and three in
Cincinnati.
Other Birds May be Saved.
Declaring that practically all the
gulls nnd terns in America today have
survived solely through the work of
protection nnd restoration at their
reservations, leaders of the National
Association of Audubon Societies are
now appealing to the people of this
country to support the work of pre
serving dying species of native birds
which they have already begun. The
Upland Plover, Cabot's Tern nnd the
Least Tern, they assert, can now be
saved to the nation by quick emer
gency measures for which special
funds are to be raised. The work of
restoring the Wood Duck and other
game birds that are threatened with
the fate of the Passenger Pigeon is to
be undertaken by the Audubon work
ers with the support of the sportsmen
of the country. Sad as is the passing
of the Passenger Tlgeon, its lesson
may avert the extinction of other val
uable species, it Is declared, If the
American people rally nt once to save
their remaining bird resources.
</text>
      </result>
		
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1913-02-21/ed-1/seq-10/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
THE PASSEN
I
By Frederic
The recent sickness of (lie passenger
pigeon in the Cinelnnai Zoological hardens?the
last survivor of a mighty host?
has served to call the attention of naturalists
again to one of the most remark|
able of all tlie stories of nature's library
?the extinction of one of the most remarkable
birds that ever inhabited the
earth. Millions of people are still living
whose eyes have witnessed the flight of
the myriad hosts of passenger pigeons,
and yet only one of all the vast numbers
of those pigeons is known to survive?
and that one occupies a place of honor
in the Cincinnati Zoo. When he dies it
is probable his body will be presented to
the nation, to be preserved in alcohol at
the National Museum.
In these days it is hard for the younger
people to believe tlie story of the passenger
pigeon, so incredible were their
numbers, so remarkable were their flights
and so strange were their nestings. And
the story of tiie brutality that marked
the work of the pot hunters who followed
them as a tiger stalks ids prey, relentlessly
pursuing them, using the telegraph
to keep in touch with their flights and
their nestings, is a story of revolting
cruelty and butchery.
The world is indebted to John James
| Audubon, the great naturalist, for what
is perhaps the best account of the passenger
pigeon ever written. And his
truthfulness and scientific accuracy made
it a story to be accepted at its face value.
He relates that in the autumn of iHl.'i he
left his house at Henderson, on the banks
of the Ohio, to go to Louisville.
* *
In passing over tlie Barrens, a few
miles front Hardensburg, he observed
pigeons llyCame
Like a Torrent, in? fr?m
, the northWith
Roar of Thunder. east tu lhe
sou tit west in greater numbers than he.
had ever seen before. After they had
been passing for about an hour lie dismounted,
seated himself on an eminence
and made a dot with a pencil for every
Hock that pussea. in a snun. mi?c ? *= j
found that ho was putting down dots at i
the rate of 163 In twenty-one minutes.
He resumed his journey and still the
pigeons came; the light of day was darkened
as if by a solar eclipse. IJke a torrent,
and with the roar of distant thunder,
they gathered in a solid mass, darting
forward with the wings of the wind
in undulating and angular lines, descending
and sweeping close to the earth, then
mounting perpendicularly so as to resemble
a vast column, and when high in
the air once more, wheeling and twisting
within their continued lines, which then
resembled the coils of a gigantic serpent.
For hity-flve miles Audubon traveled on
to Louisville, with the serried columns of |
pigeons still floating over his head, and
for three days the flight continued. Bach
flock did exactly as the one ahead had
done; If the one ahead darted down when
passing over a brook or dodging a hawk
the flock behind did the same. Audubon
attempted to estimate the number of
pigeons in that great flight. lie assumed
that the column averaged a mile in width,
which was far below the average in point
of fact. Then he assumed that the birds
flew at the rate of sixty miles an hour,
also a conservative assumption. Upon
this basis the pigeons passing in three
hours wotild form a streak 180 square i
miles in area, and, counting two pigeons !
to the square yard, there would he nearly |
a billion and a quarter pigeons in such a
flight. How many there must have been
In the three days' flight he did not undertake
to say. Audubon's observations were
that each pigeon eats fully half a pint
of food a day. Tlie pigeons in a threehour
flight would thus need nearly nine
million bushels of food a day.
*
* *
Audubon made several pilgrimages to
a famous roosting place on the banks
of the
Made Several Pilgrimages ? r e e n
to Famous Boosting Place.
tucky. He rode through the forest for
upward of forty miles, and by crossing
and recrosslng it reached the conclusion
that the roost was of an average breadth
of three mileB. His first view of it was
about two weeks after the pigeons had
established it as a roosting place. He
arrived about two hours before sunset
I7V.U7 nlmnnn tvoro tr> ho aoen hilt thero '
" I
were great numbers of people, who, with
horses and wagons, children and dogs,
guns and ammunition, had established
camps on the borders of the forest. Two
farmers had driven more than three hundred
hogs over a hundred miles to fatten
them on pigeons that were to be slaughtered.
Here and there were people engaged
in plucking and salting the catch ;
of the day before. Many trees two feet
in diameter had been broken off by the
sheer weight of the multitudes of roosting
birds. Everywhere great branches of
forest monarchs were broken off, and
the aspect of the thousands of acres of
woodland was such as one might expect
to be the result of a fierce tornado.
Some of the people who were camping
there had great pots of sulphur. Others
had poles, and others guns. It was
after sundown that the cry went up that
the returning hordes were approaching.
The noise they made reminded Audubon
of a gale at ^ea passing through the rigging
of a close-reefed vessel. As they
passed over his head he felt a current of
air that astonished him. Thousands of
birds were knocked down by the polemen.
but tens of thousands and even millions
continued to pour in. They alighted
everywhere, one above another, until
masses as large as hogsheads were
formed on tlie brandies all around.
*
* *
Here and there perches gave way under
the weight with a crash, killing hundreds
of birds
Hundreds of Birds Killed as tllcy
When the Branches Break.
tldng was uproar and confusion. The
people could not hear themselves talking
to one another, ami even the reports of
shotguns and blunderbusses could not be
1 heard above the great noise. Audubon
t a man out from the forest to see
w far the noise could be heard, and it
. is plainly audible three miles distant,
i". midnight the stream of arrivals began
to fall off, hut before the break of day
the advance guard began to move out
U'l.ilft in, dared ne in the
?*?) *! >. ? ? w
woods while the pigeons wore In the
trees, they were able to kill ami eripple
enough of theni to keep all the people
busily employed next day, with enough
left over to give the htm hogs, the wolves,
the foxes, the lynxes, the cougars, bears,
raccoons, possums, polecats, eagles and
hawks a mor>- than satisfactory breakfast.
and at the same time to sa\e enough
back for the vultures that came to supplant
the animals and the birds of prey.
James Fenltnore Cooper also saw the
flights of the passenger pigeons, and lie
said thai, in a single flight he had seen
enough birds to provision Xerxes' army
for a month and enough feathers to provide
a downy couch for every person in
the country.
The white man and his net are responsible
for the disappearance of the
passenger pigeon from the face of the
earth. They began their forays about
1H4<i. The profession of plgeoner came
into existence ami these men banded
themselves together to exploit the pigeon.
*
* *
By the telegraph they were able to
keep in close touch with the movements
of the
Used Telegraph to Keep pigeons.
\I7itb and no
44* A V UUiA VViVU ilAVVVliiVliti). .
pigeon
roost could be established for many days
before the pigeoners were on hund to
get in their deadly work. They carried
with them trained stool pigeons by which
they were enabled to rail down great
flocks of passing birds and net as many
GERPIGEON.
J. Haskin.
as tlicv possibly could park in ire and
ship. In the last great "roosting" in
Michigan in 1S7N more than ">00 tons of
tlie dressed birds were shipped out. Tens
of thousands of them were caught alive
and sold to sporting clubs for trap shooting
purposes.
o ncn some pigeoner nappeneu 10 mscover
that during the nesting season
the birds were frantic In their efforts to
ohtain salty mud and water he found a
bonanza for his ilk. Great mud beds
along streams were covered with salt
and nets were set above these. Hundreds
of thousands of parent birds would
come for their salt and water, the traps
would he sprung, and often a single net
would catch more than a thousand birds.
The pigeoners carried blacksmith pincers,
and a pinch for each captive neck, and
then a struggle, and then some starving
squabs, was the tragedy of their bloody
work.
Chief Pokagon. the last of the Pottav.attomio
chieftains of the Pokagon
band of Indians, says lie saw the pigeoners
in Penzie county. Mich., apply the
match to the mosslike dried bark of the
white birch, which burns like paper soaked
in oil, so that the flame would reach
ttie nests of the pigeons and force the
squabs to jump out. In thousands of instances
the squabs were singed alive and
the parent birds themselves had their
plumage burned badly?some so badly
that they could no longer fly.
*
* *
The pigeon butchers of yesterday were
ready with their defense when needed.
They
Pigeon Butchers Ready p ointed
With Defense of Methods. ti'uto ^ s
and the cattle and the sheep that must
be slaughtered to feed mankind. They
asserted that the pigeons were destructive.
In their own eyes they -were an
ill-used lot. Did not some one tell a
story of poisoning birds with poison
berrier. and cause the price to drop 50
cents a dozen in a single day in New
York, and to IX) cents a dozen in
Chicago? Wasn't killing pigeons with
pincers as humane as shooting quail on
the wing? The stories of great slaughttr
were, to their minds, gross exaggerations.
It has been claimed that there were
flights of passenger pigeons along the
Hudson in ItMi. and John Burroughs investigated
the report and believed It true.
A number of persons have claimed to
have small flocks of the pigeons. In 19<K?
<_*. O. Whitman of the University of Chicago,
reported to W. B. Mershon, author
of "The Passenger Pigeon," that he
had two female birds and two sterile hybrid
males.
But the passenger pigeon is gone from
the earth forever. iDike the great auk
and the buffalo it has been unable to adjust
Itself to the age of the white man
In America.
</text>
      </result>
		
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84024055/1915-05-08/ed-1/seq-8/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>THE PASSENGER PIGEON.
A Beautiful and Useful Bird That U
Now Extinct.
There are men still alive who have
shot not dozens, but hundreds, of pas
senger pigeons In a single day. Sixty
years ago this bird-was far more com
mon In the United States than wild
ducks arc today.
When It migrated the flights dark
ened the sky. A single flight has been
estimated to number over 'iOOO.OOO of
birds.
A. ter weeks ago .the last passenger
pigeon died In Chicago at the age of
twenty-seven years.
A passenger pigeon Is quite a differ
ent looking bird from any.otbcr kind of
pigeon. It has a long tall and is in all
nearly three-quarters of a yard long.
It is so called because of Its migratory
habits. It being a bird of passage.
For the past fifteen years there had
been a standing reward of 51,000 for a
mate for this last survival of her race.
This was several times Its weight in
gold, yet the offer produced no re
sponse. The passenger pigeon is abso
lutely extinct, and one of the most
beautiful and useful of birds has been
wiped out. as it were, under our very
eyes. New York Press.
</text>
      </result>
		
	<result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn86088651/1915-06-22/ed-1/seq-2/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>NO REWARD FOR PAS
SENGER PIGEONS.
Office Of Information, United Statea
Department of Agriculture.
Washington. D. C, June 22.i-Re-fent
widespread newspaper accounts
to the effect that the United States De
partment of Agriculture Is offering
tlO.000 reward to the person find'ng
a psM-nger cr "wood" pigeon test
rnii o
containing two eggs, resulted in hun
dreds of letters being sent to the de
partment. The report la not based
upon facta aa the department baa ot
tered no such reward, and there Is
every i reason to believe tha passen
ger pigeon which formerly roamed
the country In flocks of millions Is
extinct. In 1910 about $1.00.) In re
wards were offered by Clark Univer
sity for tha first undisturbed nests
of the passenger pigeon to be found
In the United States, This waa a
great stimulus to action. The hunt for
this pigeon waa fruitless. The offer
ot rewards was renewed for several
years until It was fully established
that the pigeon waa extinct
. The passenger pigeon up to 1S8J
ranged the American continent east
of the Rocky Mountains. The mourn
ing dove baa often been mistaken for
the passenger pigeon, which in a gen
eral way it resembles. However, this
bird Is quite distinct from the passen
ger pigeon; it Is shorter and hss dif
ferent color markings.
Tbe press reorts stated that the
now extinct passenger plgon was vsK
ued because cf its usefulness In de
stroying the gipsy moth and other
moths and pests which are doing mil
lions of dollars of damage. Although
the preservation of this pigeon l
much to be desired. It would be of ab
solutely no value In eliminating the
gipsy moth as the pigeons are slniot
entirely vegetarian In their diet.

</text>
      </result>

	<result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82015761/1916-06-22/ed-1/seq-5/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Passenger Pigeon Not Extinct
The passenger pigeon . which 50
years ago was th most numerous
game bird on the continent, ' is not
extinct as has. been supposed. . The
destruction of these birds for com
mercial purposes was enormous.
yet to some unknown agency must
be attributed the sudden disappear
ance of the enormous flock which
made their annual passage from
their summer quarters in the far
north to their winter home in the
south.
Quite recently sportsmen have
noticed a few of these birds in the
Santa Fe Canyon of New Mexico.
The birds are well protected by
law and it is hoped that thru such
protection and - the protection
which game protective associations
vill give them these birds may
multiply and again become numerous.
</text>
      </result>

		
    </results>
	  
  </topic>
	
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-motorcycle-mania/introduction</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/item/sn85042591/1869-01-22/ed-1/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
	    
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/item/sn82015104/1895-11-16/ed-1/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>

	<result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/item/sn83030214/1903-09-08/ed-1/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>

	<result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/item/sn83030214/1903-11-02/ed-1/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>R. G. Bctts's Sen-ices to Motor
cycling The Kennel Shore.
One of the most active workers among motor
cyclist* is R. G. Betts. the arastdaßl of the Feder
ation of American Motorcyclists. Mr. Betfs was
recently elected to this office. The purpose of the
organization is to "encourage the use of motor
cycles and to promote th* reneral Interests of
motorcycling; to ascertain, defer.d and protect the
rights of motorcyclists; to facilitate tour.- to
assist In th* pood roads movement and to advise
and assist in the regulation of motorcycle racing
end other competitions In which motorcycles en
gage." He became Interested In motorcycles while
living In Boston in 1900. his first experter.ee being
R. O. BETTS.
President of the Federation of American Motor
cyclists.
paired on a rented tricycle. In August cf that
V'..ir he sought to creir.iz" the Brst American
motorcycle club, and isM.er! a call ti.it brought
together MM fourteen riders. The meeti! ran
away from its stated purpose, ar.,i. against Mr.
Betts protest, resolved Itself into a '•national"
organisation, Btyled the A?soeiited American Mo
torcyclists. Mr. Betts is a native of Sew-Orleans
and has been connected with bicycle journals for
many rears. Be is now th<- editor of the motor
and bicycle publications publish i by the
rr,:i:-. my. He Id a member of the New-
Tort Mot. Club and the Alpha Motorcycle
Club, and was c: of the foui len I the Uetropole
SS y J v^ C! H« ;s; s also a delegate of the Asso
ciated Cycling Clubs,</text>
      </result>

	          <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/item/sn83030272/1904-07-20/ed-1/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>NOTORnCLES FOR POLICE POLICEUrhlnes POUCEIfthlnn POrICElachtnes
Urhlnes in OH Urlns ntln Tried Out for forSelection torS forSrlectlon
Selection S llltlon for a Squirt Squirtf SquadThrouah qualtf
f Throueh certain motorcycle riders and andrlralers andrlmlerll an4rlralers
rlralers it in reported that New York or at atIfast litIMllt atleast
least Manhattan borough Is to have a amotorcycle atnotorcycfI atnotnrcyele
motorcycle police squad Inspector Smith Smithit
it Is said lId has become a I convert to the Idea Ideaever Idoapr Ideaever
ever pr since the general adoption about a ayoarngo aflrago aycarago
yoarngo of the grip control which which enables enablesa
a rider to start and step and regulate his hisi hisBPped
p i P speed on one or the e power cycles with one onenand
I hand and without removing it from the theHlecrlng theIeering thesteedng
Hlecrlng bar barA barA barA
A number of members of the New York YorkMotorcycle YorkIMotorcYCle
IMotorcYCle Motorcycle Club and several dealer have haveIeen havePen
len Pen Interviewed by the Inspector with a aview
view Iew to selecting tho best make of machine machineon machineRnd machineand
and several varieties have been tried out outon outtl
on tl the th road by b officers Two patrolmen patrolmenv
v are nr now covering posts on motorcycles motorcyclesratrolman
1 6 1 ratrolman Ennls on Riverside Drive being beingone beingline beingof
one of them themAccording themi themAccording
i According Cordlng to Inspector Smith the only
thing that stands in the way of an Irame Irameiltate ImmellalLate 1mmclit
iltate llalLate clit formation of a motorcycle squad Is Islack IIok
lack ok of funds He considers the machine machinenecessary miohlneanocMaSry machinesnesaary
necessary for chasing c automobiles and run runi rullaal runsways
sways Q4 a4be he hope to be able to get U1e U1emon tkiI
sum money for r rtb tbttabet th Iier tor or i loac loajj
</text>
      </result>

	          <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/item/sn85042462/1905-10-11/ed-1/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>POLICE ON MOTORCYCLES WILL
CHASE SPEED MAD AUTOISTS
The imperative demand of the legis
lative committee of the city council to
know why the speed ordinances regu
lating automobiles is not enforced has
been productive of results and the
city council has been requested by the
police commission to purchase two
motorcycles for the benefit of the police
department.
When these motorcycles are secured
and put In commission, woe betide the
motorist who drives his machine faster
than Is reasonable and proper for pub
lic safety. Commissioner Gates Intro
duced the recommendation before the
board yesterday that the council be
Instructed to purchase two of the best
motorcycles that money can buy and
have them equipped with the nsst In
struments for determining: speed.
"Two motorcycles! Two shotguns Is
what we need," was the Indignant ex
plosion of Commissioner James.
Whether Mr. James favored the swift
execution of the speed mad motorist
or would have the Bhotguns used to
puncture the tires was a question of
which he left the commission In doubt.
It was agreed by the commission that
two motorcycles were not enough, but
that it would do for an experiment
and If the results proved satisfactory
more would be ordered.
"We formerly arrested and sometimes
secured convictions of those who ex
ceeded the speed limit, but that wan
when we had an automobile that was
furnished by the Southern California
Automobile association to be used for
that purpose. That automobile hns
been taken away from us and sinca
then we have not been able to catch
the violators of the law.
"With two motorcycles we can keep
		up with an automobile, however fust
it is being run, and if we cannot then
arrest the violators we can at least
see the number of the machines and
perhaps identify those who are in It
and have warrants issued for them.
But without the motorcycles we are
powerl3Sß to do anything."
It was the opinion of the mayor that
the speed ordinance should be entirely
abolished and the question of whether
or not motor vehicles were being run
too fast left to the discretion of the
officers to make arrests, whenever they
believed such action was Justified.
It was pointed out, however, by Com
missioners James and Gates, both of
whom are practicing attorney*!, thut
under such a condition there would be
no evidence to present to the courts
iind secure a conviction. Section four
of the speed ordinance provides that
at no time shall a motor vehicle be
run faster than Is reasonable and
proper with regard to public safety.
The maximum limit at which automo
biles may be run in the business Jin
trlct Is twelve mile 3an hour and no
more than four miles an hour while
crossing street Intersections.
"The entire solution of the problem
Is to have a law paßsed by the United
Plates government, making It a crime
to construct automobiles which are
capable of a speed greater than ten or
twelve miles an hour," said Mayor
McAleer, "and the indications are thnt
such a law will soon be passed. The
manufacturers of motor vehicles
thrughout the country recognise that
such a law is lnpvltable and are now
working on models of this type of
machine to be ready for the mnrkfrt
with slow machines when the lav/ Is
passed."

</text>
      </result>
	<result>
		
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/item/sn85042462/1908-09-09/ed-1/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>

	          <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/item/sn85066387/1910-07-31/ed-1/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>

	</result>

	<result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/item/sn98047754/1911-09-01/ed-1/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>The Motorcycle on the Farm.
If one is to believe tbe statements
of tbe leading motorcycle maufac
turers of the day and their statements
seem logical, it is cheaper to make a
trip to town on a motorcycle than to
drive or walk. A manufacture of one
of these motorcycles (his particular
make holds the world's record for
economy) states thnt while the ma
chine that made the world's record
traveling fifty miles at a cost of less
than one-tenth cent per mile over
country road 9 was operated by an ex
pert, it is nothing unusual for this
particular make of motorcycle in the
bands of an amateur to travel from
six to eight miles on one cent's worth
of gasoline.
Id comparison with the private rid
ing horse the expense per mile is
naturally much less and if one figures
that while the driving horse must be
fed daily, the motorcycle only con
sumes while in use, the difference is
still greater. The limit of a horse for
continuous daily driving is probably
thirty miles, while that of a motor
cycle is over two hundred. Good
traveling for a road horse means ten
miles an hour; good traveling for
a motorcycle from thirty to fifty
miles per hour.
In this age of scaroe hired help,
time, at some season is extremely
valuable to the farmer. His ability
to oover the distance to town and
back with a motorcycle in one fifth of
the road driving horse time and with
no time wasted harnessing and un
harnessing, is a factor to be consider
ed.
Most all tbe good motorcycles are
now equipped with tandem attach
ments and luggage carriers, if desired.
By means of this tandem attachment
two can ride as well as one. The
luggage carrier permits tbe carrying
of small freight, not exoeeding 200
pounds.
Many a farmer, as well as his child
ren, have rebelled at their inability
to go to town, to the swimming hole
or the fishing grounds in the late
summer evening, for a horse cannot
be worked all day and be driven on
the road at night. To these the
motorcycle fills a long felt want. It
is ever ready, costs nothing when idle
and will last for years.
It is really more expensive to be
without a motorcycle than to own
one, just as it is more expensive to
plow with a hand plow, cradle the
grain and use the flail instead of the
modern appliances. The best makes
of motorcycle today can be had for
from $225 up. A motorcycle like
many other pieces of machinery, can
be built too cheaply to be good.
There are, however, several well
established makes, which have years
of successful manufacture behind
them and one will not go amiss in
choosing any of these.
The motorcycle of today has come
to stay. Already in the cities it is
being adopted extensitvely by busi
ness firms because of the great time
saving its use assures.
Repair men, inspection men, etc,
can accomplish triple the work pos
sible with their former horse and
carriage. The saving of time as well
as the great pleasure to be derived
from its use has given the motorcycle
a lasting place in the home c f the
American farmer.

</text>
      </result>

	          <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/item/sn83045462/1915-02-07/ed-1/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>MOTOR CYCLES INVADE
I ALL FIELDS OF ACM
4
II
Preacher. Doctor, Policeman and
J! Soldier Now Use TwoWheeled
Vehicles.
<1
Hundreds of daily demonstrations are
fcroof of the utility, speed and economy j
Of the modern motor cycie. meic >e i
earcely a field of activity that the two- J
wheeler has not entered and proved its
^falue. i
The motor cycle carries the minister)
to reach his patient in less time than ever
before, making: it possible to eliminate
many hours of human suffering.
The motor cycie carried the minister
of th^ gospel on his missions of mercy.
The motor cycle is a part of every progressive
police department, carrying
mounted officers to the scene of crime or
accident, and enabling them to run down
Violators of the law.
The motor cycle aids the forest ranger
ifi protecting our great timber lands from
'lire.
The motor cycle carries mail and delivers
telegrams.
The motor cycle rushes the important
prescription to the bedside of the suf^tVring.
The motor cycle hurries the pulmotor
tj. the beach, where every second counts,
(he effort to restore life.
motor cycle mounted guard accompanies
the I'resident of the United States
his trir.s about the capital.
Motor Cycle in War.
ses of the motor cycie in the army are
almost unlimited. Motor cycle dispat-Ti
riders and scouts have won great fame
Car themselves in the present European
'^iruggle. Machine guns mounted on
motor cycles are carried to their positions
the battlefield motor cycles with sidecars
hurry vsupplies to the lted Cross
workers who are seeking to relieve the i
figured soldiers to the hospitals.
"The motor cycle has revolutionized sig- I
naling on the battlefield," says Henry j
Beach Needham, a war correspondent.
"It has practically done away with wigwagging
on the field. It is economical,
efficient and speedy, and is everywhere
and nowhere as much as at the front."
lTor pleasure, too, the motor cycle has
made a definite place for itself. The ease
with which the two-wheeler is operated,
iis reliability and comfort, make it ail
ideal vehicle for touring. Club sociability
awl endurance runs are enjoyed by thou
oumis of riders all over the couutrv everv
Year.
And more and more we hear of the
ir.nff./ii?t.Jnc. tourist rldinc from ocean i
to ocean, l'rom gulf to lake, around the j
Limited States or circling the globe?tor j
pleasure. Many of those long-distance j
tourists art women, who find as ranch j
Pi casure in the sport as do the men.
	MOTOR CYCLE NOTES.
111
The Capital City Motor Cycle Club
of Sacramento, Cal., is making an effort
to secure the 100-mile national
championship for its annual spring
meet.
It has been decided that the next
national motor cycle, bicycle and accessories
show will be held in the Coliseum
in Chicago September L'Q-25.
Sanction has just been issued by the
Federation of American Motor Cyclists
i or a iuu-mne moior cycle meei iu uc
held at Calesbuiig, 111., July
The Wheeling" (W. Va.) Motor Cycle
Club is planning: to have a tri-state
reunion of motor cyclists during the
coming- summer.
In planning for the coming season's
events the Worcester (Mass.) Motor
Cycle Club has set Patriots' day, April
10, for the opening run, which will be
to Concord, Lexington and return.
Though less than two months old,
(the motor cycle club of St. Paul, Minn.,
has reached a membership mark of 100.
lit is the purpose of the club to raise
this to 250 by next fall.
A ifew motor cycle dub has been
formed in Cincinnati, Ohio, known as
the Queen City M. C. It has twentytwo
charter members. The organization
is planning to affiliate with the
F. A. M.
A. Y. Letts of Ilohoken, X. J., has
made his motor cycle help him earn
quite a bit of money this winter. He
attached the motor to a skate sharpener,
with which he has kept the
skates of the community in good condition.
Frank Middleton of Atlantic City,
X'. J., whose business is the painting
of show cards anrl large signs, uses a
motor cycle to take him #er the city
in quest of new business.
A retail shoe concern of Chicago has
used a motor cycle in working out a
novel advertising scheme. Mounted on
the two-wheeler is a traveling show
case in which the latest models of
shoes are displayed. The motor cycle i
is also used for firactical delivery purposes.
I
Nearly 200 riders and their friends
participated in the recent annual >>an-
quet of the Rockford fill.) Motor Cycle
Club.
Order Eight-Cylinder Kings.
Orders have been placed with the local j
representative for King "Eight" touring
cars as follows: H. S- Thompson, D. j
Scott Thompson and D. M. Gamble.
Purchasers of Cadillacs.
During the past week seven-pas-
senger 1915 Cadillac touring cars were
delivered to W. E. Montgomery. Mrs.
V. R. Tsenberg and Col. A. M hedon.
U. S. A.
Mexican Embassy Buys Hudson.
The Mexican embassy has purchased
a 1915 6-40 Hudson touring car. fully
equipped. Delivery was made a lew
days ago.
On Territory Trip.
Walter U Smith, local representative
for the Argo and Detroiter cars,
is spending several days in Virginia
in the interest of these cars. He left
Thursday night and is expected to return
Tuesday night of this week.
A New Franklin Owner.
The latest purchaser of a 1915 Franklin
6-30, five-passenger touring car is
Charles D. Sager, delivery being made
during the past week.
To Represent Acme Tire.
The Pollock Car Corporation has closed
a contract to represent the Acme red letter
tire in the National Capital.

	</text>
      </result>

    </results>
  </topic>

	
  <topic>
    <id></id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/item/sn96027111/1909-04-30/ed-1/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Whoe Urittd Sttti to Honor
i t 11if K iinSuodiy May sT
i MtIACK HOME IF YOU CAN
t 1 1
WMto CarafrliM WH i W r s by All
t v y na Fr Clitiir
3 Jlt k MiArms J his f hlirrrid It hla
f T Vvvv lHfl i MP WH v f H b4t wwT L
r t to tW Hir
It Bey
F
0
T H Mcc M Udty 1D
J i r wkl be cekbrate this year la
trtcy H4tSoa of the Halted States
L b t J f oc the art tilde the deed
4 et v pJofM Bx tbers will bt given
Petal recognition by the military of
k th TJalted States General Edgar
iHtB lr1 commander in chief of the
Ns tal Veterans has been the first
I Mcs to recognise the merit of the
4K Btration and has issued orders
Y oj
to his comrades for a general observ
f t ance Mothers day
t la fate notice General Allen says A
treat movement has been inaugurated
to4o boor to our mothers Our
netherc are oar best friends No day
i has ever been set aside for the honor
ing of their heroic deeds and memory
f Toa will do honor to yourselves your
p fathers and your mothers by observ
I ing thif event In an appropriate way
No word of mine can add to the many
lavdable reasons why we as Sons of
1 Veterans should honor this event
Tie sponsor for this celebration is
f j MJsjl Anna Jarvis of 2031 North
Tyelfth street Phlladelpbla The first I
effort to call the attention of the entire
United States to the proposed celebra
tion jras made one year ago Like
h BMny home products it received great
er er recognition in other parts of the
cwantry Throughout the south and
west the idea spread with wonder
i i f J rapidity until mass meetings and
Hiblic demonstrations of other kinds
were organized and held before large
amerces
Necessarily of a sentimental origin
and meaning the celebration assumed
y I its most significant aspect in the state
t r prisons and penitentiaries The grim
1 will of Leavenworth Cherry Hill
Sing Sing and Nebraska prisons lost
Hot a little of their sordldness and
p hearts that had not been otherwise
accessible were touched maybe only
for the iaqtant in some cases but even
R t shadow otthe mother thought that
r fell left an impression that prompted
f i k t the men to look forward to the celebration
C
i bration this year More than that
a r wbjfe cargat1onathe symbol of the
day and that which U celebratesare
to hi given to the men Letters from
t prisoners to governors of their states
r w asking for just an hours relief from
the discipline governing them I have
met wIth approval and services will
k x be held In the stone corridors and in
the prison yards
Hiss Jarvis has been the recipient of
many touching letters In a feeble
x hand that spoke volumes of sorrow
and trial a woman who simply sign
ph ed herself His Mother told a typical
tale of broken heart In her letter
r this woman praised Miss Jarvis for
k r her godly thought and said HI have
f a son and three daughters They are
all good to me I want for nothing us
t I need but little I am very feeble
and T know that I have not much
longer to live He writes to me and
jl 1 when he gives me an address I write
to him He is so kind to me He sends
l m g money and everything but will not
come home He Is wandering all over
i Y the world and I want him to come to
K his home if only for one night IfJ
rt
could only see him and tell him how I
love him I should feel that all the good
1 ness that God intended for me in my
11 old age was mine I do not want his
r i money I am saving ft all for him
But oh if he would only come to me
J before I die I should be so happy
1 Please prqy for my boy with roe and
ask that he be sent home
In this spirit which surely appeals
ft t to every man and woman wear u
c r white carnation on the second Sunday
t in May and keep in your heart the
thought of your mother Go home If
you can If you cant hold silent com
munion with her for her thought will
r surely be of you
Miss Jarvis original idea embraced
tf
the simultaneous observance In every
l part of the world of the love and rev
I erence which all men and women owe
r their mothers The white carnation
was especially chosen because of Its
i 1 whiteness which stands for purity Its
V form and fragrance representing
It beauty and love Its wide field of
f growth and lasting qualities symbol
I izing charity and faithfulness a
l true mothers virtues
</text>
      </result>
	    
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/item/sn84026749/1909-05-09/ed-1/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>MOTHERS A TRIBUTE TRIBUTEWhite
White Flowers Are Worn in inHonor inHOhor inHotior
Honor of the Pas Passion Paso Passion Passion
o
sion SublimeIt Sublime
It Mothers Day does nothing el else e It Itought itought t tought
ought to create sentiment for an l indusrial indus industrial dutrial
trial t inuranc that th tt wJI II If lilt It a crushing cruaWhisload crushingoad rU811tugloild
load l from the women Wl en and children c U4ren of ofAmerica f fAmerica
America AmericaThis AmericaThis
This sentence from 111 the sermon s nICJ tot f tha thaRev UI UIRe tbRev
Rev Re John Van Schaick at the morningscrhe morning morningservice mondngcrvleo
service of the Church of Our Father Fatherreflects F 1therreflects lher
reflects the sentiment that mis this thiscountry thiscountry
country today tOdayin in its U observance of ofMothers orIolhcrs ofMothers
Mothers Day Pu Pulptt ptt platform and andhome andborne
home throughout the tIi nation are giving givingforth givingforth
forth ther tributes trlbut to the motherhood motherhoodof
of the land the white carnation or the thewhite thfwhite thewhite
white rose as a symbol of purity may maybe maybe maybe
be seen everywhere as illtel evidence evidencethat eldencuthat e1dencethat
that the wearer loves to honor his moth mother
er living 01 her memory if deed deedThe l1tedrhe dearhe
rhe significance of Mothers Day D ythe ytheobservance the theobservance theobservance
observance of which originated orfgl 8ted with withMiss wtthMiss 1th
Miss Anna Jarvis of Philadelphia has hasspread ba basprcatl hasspread
spread into 1ni the innds and D gripped the thehearts Ll1ehearts
hearts of men everywhere every here 11 several severalof Mt ral ralor
of the States the governors liey h1J prr prrclglmcd prr prrclaimed prvcisirned
claimed the s second cond Siiday SId y in jay ay OK OKthe R8the asthe
the Say da and in a number of oftl Uelrge Uelrgecities ellIrte larger largercities
I I
cities the mayors mRy tIH are leaden Ii it I is ob observance obscrvtlncc
servance scrvtlnccNo
No Creed In Observance ObservanceIn
In Waahlngtoa the oboervamre rva1ke is wide widespread wideaproa6 widesinend
spread It Is ar ol observance rvance thAt know knowno knowsno ko koQ
no creed no ft dl cbsiinctfon tinetion oC wealth or orposition Oposition orposition
position its spirit as exproMed In Inchurches Inchurch2I inchurches
churches Sunday schools schOol lodge rooms roomsarid roolJUlarid roomsand
arid societies Is universal universalAt
At the Young Alons Mon s Christian Chrl Uan Associa Association Aneoclation SIIOCiatlon
tion the day wac especially obfcarved obfcarvedMost Gbat cbiervedMost rved rved11ost
Most of the members wore th the emble emblematic ernbiematic mblematte
matic flower Lato this afterriwio afterriwiomeeting afteat afterziooflmeeting o a ameeting
meeting fur or men will wl 1 be beheld held In n the thegymuosicm theSTIIlnasicm thisgyinnasicin
gymuosicm 1736 1 strset and at Atodoc1 4 4oclock 4ocloclc
oclock the Rev Re George Galley alley pastor pastorof IJ tor torof
of the Western Presbyterian Prc bytcrhm Churcti Churctiwill Chprciwill h1Jr f1 f1wfll
will deliver an adUrese un The Iawslon IawslonSublime laltdonSubUmc 1astenSuhhIme
Sublime SublimeIt
It was fitting that from on one of the theloading theloading theleading
loading pulpits of the Capital should shouldissue shouldIlMIue shouldimue
issue an appeal to mento men to acknowledge acknowledgetheir acknowledgetheir
their lusting obligation to motherhood motherhoodand
and to honor it wth all the strength strengthand sttenstband sttengikand
and devotion of manhood Tne Re ReJohn ReJohn RetJohn
John Van Schaick not only asked that thatand tbAtMothors thatMothers
Mothers Day be given general ob observance ohservance
servance but fervontly advoc adv cited citedadoption ted the theadoptJon
adoption be 8 a Rtvernmental meae meastireand re reand
and safeguard reguard of some form of man Insiranco bunrance manance
ance that would free dependent depcn ent moth mothers motJlera mothera
era fromthe lrom the sting stingof of poverty that tliatCol tliatCollows fol folj el ellowe
j lows the death of the breadwinner brMdWln r Ded DedIcating DedIcatiniO Didicating
Icating hfe ht serfrrbn erlm n to The he Da of th thWhIte the the1llto theWhiIte
WhIte 1llto Flower Dr Van Scha Schafck ck said saidBurden saIdBurden saidBurden
Burden Upon Mothers MothersAs
As society Is organized today tod It It1laces ftl ItiiaOS
1laces l IIS S too heavy a a burden on the moth mothers moUJOIS motlore
ers If Ita a wageworker is killed at his hispost hispo hisport
post po t in Germany the financial burden burdenIg burden burdenJg
Jg divided between and wife and moth mother
er the employe and state Hero the themothor themothor themother
mothor bears it all If Mothers Day Daydoes Dayd
does d es s nothing else it If ought to tocro create createsentiment createsentiment te te80ntlment
sentiment fr f an industrial Insurance Insurancethat In8urancethat Insurancethat
that will lift n crushing load from tho thowomon thowomen thewomen
women and children of America AmericaI
I doubt if ever a Mothers Day could couldbe couldbe couldbe I
be established c by law but I have no nodoubt nldoubt nodoubt
doubt but what vith little effort the thecustom thecustom thecustom
custom could could1x be Jlrmly established eslabU hcd In Inchurches Inehurch9 inchurches
churches and hrmes of having one day dayespecially dayelpeciolly dayespecially
especially set atfart and dedicated to toour toour teour
our mothers No Instinct is I so strong strongin
in humanity a ao tho Instinct In Unct of mother motherhood motherood motherlood
hood ood No love lov that we ever have near nearus nearUlil neazus
us Is as a much to us or some of us at atlodst atIMBt atleast
least as a the loveof our mothers No Noservice NOrvlcc Nrservice
service rvlcc rendered to the community or orthe ortho orthe
the nation natlol or r the rape is 1 as great aa a athat asthat j
that of ortbo the hidthprs irlcit1irsThink indthersThink i iThink
Think first of the typical mother motherthat motherthat mothertht
that ideal mother the Blessed Ble ed Mary Marymother Marymother Marymother
mother of Christ Mary ought to oc occupy occupy
cupy a higher Jtl her place In our affections affectionsthan aJrecUonsthan affectionsthan I
than she he does What is called marl marlolatry marlolatry
olatry or the adoration of the Virgin VirginMary VirginMary VirginMary I
Mary accounts for some failure to tostudy toIIlud tcstudy
study IIlud and understand and ane reverence her herbeautiful herbeauUful
beautiful character Marlolatry Is an anopprobrious anos anopprobrious I
opprobrious os term applied by some somoProtestants someProte I
Protestants Prote tant to the veneration of the theVirgin theVirgin i Ii
tint
Virgin by Roman Catholics I itO to o not notsympathize notlIympathlze no nosympathize t
sympathize with these Protestants Proteata Protestasitsdo I Ido Io
do o appreciate the love and reference referenceof reerenceor reVerencof
of Catholics for or Mary MaryTribute MaryTribute MaryTribute
Tribute To Mary MaryIn Maryconclusion
In conclusion Dr Van Schaick paid paidtribute pldtribute I Itribute
tribute to Mary air a the ideal of woman womanhood womanhood womanhood
hood the standard from which all other otherwomen otherwomen r rwomen
women should draw inspiration and andhigher andhigher ani I Ihigher
higher life lifeIn lICeIn lifelfl
In some way wa he added iMary tuy has hasbecome hasbecome ha habecome
become the friend of the friendless friend I the tis tishelpor
helper of the helpless the hope of the thehopeless thehopelcSfS tb tbhopeless
hopeless When we think of the sacri sacrifice sacrifice sacrilice
fice on Calvary let us remember that thatthere thatthere the t tthere
there stood by t te e arose of Jesus hie hiemother hJaO1er hi S Srnoi1er
mother O1er Her sacrifice W a symbol of ofthst ofthat a f fthat
that ma made do by b moUiaiw In all age 8810 Their Theirsncriflcs Theirsncrlfice r rsacrifice
sacrifice for us calls its 1 to the support supportwomen flUpportot supper t tof
ot laws that will m make lce the lives of al 11 11omen 1 1women
women sweeter freer and tr 1irtshtel giU r
1
</text>
      </result>

	          <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/item/sn85066387/1912-05-11/ed-1/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>BOYS AND GIRLS
TO PAY TRIBUTE
Sons and Daughters Unite to
Commemorate Mothers'
Day in the City
How many of the Juniors have
heard of JMiss Annie Jarvis?
She is the Avoman who brought
about the establishment of a
"mothers' day" in almost every
stale in the union, not to mention
the nations of the world and
whose indefatigable efforts have
served to arouse in every man,
woman and child a sense of the
beauty of motherhood and the
duty we owe to our mothers.
Miss Jarvis is a Philadelphia
woman. A few years ago, alone
and unaided she started the
"mothers' day" movement, and so
eloquent was her plea that the
idea found instant and hearty ac
ceptance. Since then the plan has
been gaining ground and within
the last four years the setting
aside of a mothers' day has been
accepted and indorsed by nearly
every governor in the union and
many of the crowned heads of Eu
rope.
"Mothers' day" falls on the sec
ond Sunday of May.
Tomorrow is the day when the
Junior boys and girls pay special
court to mother. On all the other
holidays, remember, mother pays
special attention to you, but on
the second Sunday in May condi
tions are reversed a bit and moth
er comes in for the lion's share
of pleasures.
See if you can't do something
especially nice for her tomorrow.
Show her how much you care for
her and how very dear she is to
you. Help.her with the work
around the house, wait on her for
a change and give her the benefit
of her holiday.
"Mothers* day" will be celebrat
ed in many of the churches tomor**
row, but that is not enough, boys
and girls. It should be celebrated
in your hearts as well. There is
no one in all the world who will
do as much for you as will your
mother. When every one else has
forsaken you and you haven't a
friend on earth, your mother will
stand by you with words of en
couragement and love.
See if you can't make her to
morrow a very pleasant one in
deed.
The white carnation has been
chosen as the flower symbolical
of filial devotion and the florists
are crowding their windows with
the beautiful emblems of purity
and love, for everyone's going to
make a big bow to mother tomor
row.
Don't forget to wear a white
carnation and wish mother the
happiest returns of the day.
</text>
      </result>

	          <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/item/sn86063381/1912-05-11/ed-1/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text>Mother's Day.
"Backward, turn backward, O Time,
in thy flight,
Make me a child again, just for a
night'
Mother, come back from the echoless
shore,
Take me again to your heart as of
yore,
Kiss from my forehead the furrows
of care,
Smooth the few silver threads out of
my hair
Over my slumbers your loving watch
keep,
Rock me to sleep, mother, rock me
to sleep Wear a Flower.
"White flower for Mother dead
Bright flower for Mother living
It was five years ago that Miss An-
na Jarvis, of Philadelphia, con-
ceived the idea of selecting one day
of the year upon which the devotion
to mothers' memory should be ob-
served, and the second Sunday in
May being the day upon which fell
the anniversary of her mother's
death, that day was chosen by her as
Mothers' day.
Miss Jarvis wrote to churches, so-
cieties, public officials, noted people
and the press and all joined in the
movement which she had originated
It has spread so rapidly that this
year a majority of the governors of
states have issued proclamations set-
ting aside tomorrow as Mothers' day
and suggesting that it be made one of
the state's memorial days.
The original plan was that each
one wishing to honor his mother
would wear a white carnation, but
the demand proving greater than the
supply, it was decided to wear a
white carnation for the dead and a
bright flower for the living So wear
a flower tomorrow, white or bright,
"in honor of the best mother in the
world, your mother."
</text>
      </result>

	          <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/item/sn85038615/1912-05-12/ed-1/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>

	          <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/item/sn84026749/1914-05-07/ed-1/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>

	          <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/item/sn83045433/1914-05-10/ed-1/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Mr. Wilson
--v i
WASHINGTON CLERGYMEN JOIN
Wear a White Carnation
President Is Highly Praised
for Recognizing Movement
by Issuing National Proc
lamation; This la "Mothers Day."
Throughout the city, and In every Part
of the United States, the people are ob
serving the one day In the year dedi
cated to the mothers of the race.
Prominent "clergymen and members of
the laity Joined In expressions of appre
ciation yesterday, for the act cf the
President In issuing a proclamation, of
ficially designating the second Sunday
in May as Mothers' Day." This action
comes as a result of the Senate's adop
tion of the resolution offered by Senator
Sheppard, asking the President to offl
clally designate "Mothers' Day."
Wrnr a While Carnatton.
The white carnation will be wom by
thousands In Washington, the carnation
being; the symbol of "Mothers' Day."
Local florists, however, have served no
tice that the carnation supply Is short
this spring and it is quite likely that
white flowers of other varieties also will
be worn.
Mgr. William T. Russell, pastor St.
Patrick's Catholic Church. In. a state
ment prepared for the Washington Herald
yesterday, said:
"The decision of Congress and the
President to recognize officially, one
day In the year when the mothers of
the nation will be honored by the
whole people. Is a most laudable art.
No nation can rise higher than the
standard of its mothers and to the
mothers of America we owe what
ever (we have gained in the movement
tonard a higher and nobler type of
American manhood and womanhood."
RevTJr. Abram Simon, pastor of the
Washington Hebrew Congregation, also
commented on the observance of "Moth
ers' Day-"
'Mothers' Day." finds a most
hearty" welcome In the household of
Israel." said Dr. Simon. "With us.
her due and our duty have become
proverbial for purity, affection and
devotion. From the patriarchal day
.until this, motherhood has spoken
wilh a Hebrew accent. But mother
hood was not detached from father
hood obligations. It is parenthood
Proclaims "Mothers' Day''

President's Proclamation Calling for the
Observance Today of Mothers' Day
Whereas, by a Joint resolution
second Sunday In May as Mothers"
ldent Is authorized and requested
government officials to display
buildings, and the people of the
homes or other suitable places orBr
expression of our love and reverenSTor the mothers of our country;
And whereas, by ihe said Joint-resolution It is made the duty of the
President to request the observance of the second Sunday In May as
provided for in the said Joint resolution:
Now, therefore, I, Woodrow Wilson, President of the United States of
America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the said Joint reso
lution, do hereby direct the government officials to display the United
States flag on all government buildings and do Invite the people of the
United States to display the flag at their homes or other suitable places
on the second Sunday In -May as a public expression of our love and rever
ence for the mothers of our country.
In witness whereof I have set my hand and caused the seal of the
United States to be heVeunto affixed.
Done at the city of Washington this 9th day of May, In the year of
our Lord one thousand nine hundred and fourteen, and of the Independ
ence of the United States one hundred and thirty-eighth.
(Seal.) WOODROW WILSON,
By the President:
WILLIAM JENNINGS BRYAN.
Secretary of State.
which needs emphasis and ceaseless
devotion. I believe In mothers. I
believe in 'Mothers' Day.' and I be
lieve in mothers' duty. But I believe
that It ought to be of practical value.
Mother's Day.' Is, after all. a wom
an's creation, but It must become a
man's Institution."
Apprnln to Mothers.
Rev. James Shera Montgomery, pastor
of Metropolitan Memorial M. E. Church,
said:
"May God help the mothers to know
that they were never so much needed
as' today. Little children want them:
lost men and women need them;
Christ will be blessed In many a
home by their precepts, and I urge
the mothers of the country to keep
close to the heart of the world, that
they may know it better."
"Mother's Day" services will be held
in many of the churches of Washington
this morning and a number of Washing
ton pastors have announced that they
will make the day the subject of their
morning and evening sermons. "Mother's
Day" has been observed in the United
States for a number of years, although
it was never before officially recognized
by the government through a Presi
dential proclamation.
It has been known for some time that
Representative Heflln anticipated intro
ducing a resolution asking the House
to request the President to Issue a
proclamation, officially calling atten
tion to the observance of "Mothers"
Day." When Representative Heflln In
troduced his resolution It went through
the House without protest, and when
carried to the Senate It was Immediately
taken In charge by Senator Sheppard, of
Texas.
The measure was brought before the
Senate Friday and Immediate action was
obtained, and when the President was
acquainted with the action of the Senate
he promptly had prepared and Issued the
proclamation.
		
</text>
      </result>

	          <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/item/sn85058396/1916-05-19/ed-1/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Our Latest Addition To the Calendar oHolidaysIs
I But a Revival of Mothering Sunday of the Sev-
enteenth Century The Mother Influence
In Our National Life.
(l Copyright, 1910, by Tho International Syndicate.
"Whereas, liy a Joint Resolution np
proved May 8th, 1914, designating tho
second Sunday in May as Mothers'
i Day and for other purposes, tho Presi
dent is authorized nnd requested to
issuo a proclamation calling upon the
i Government officials to display the
United States Flag on all Government
buildings, nnd tho peoplo of the
United States to display tho flag at
their homes or other suitable places
on tho second Sunday In May as a
pnblio expression of our lovo and rev
erence for the mothers of our country.
And Whereas, by the said joint Rcs
olution it is made tho duty of the
President to request the observation
J of the second Sunday in May as pro
j Tided for In the said joint Resolution;
Now, Therefore, I, Wooclrow Wfl
rj son, President of the United States
;J of America, by virtue of the authority
vested in mo by the said Joint Rcso
lution, do hereby direct tho Govern-
i W11 above, a proclamation by the
3 M President of the United States,
i added another day to the calen
j dar of our national holidays and
yone which has a tender significance
j and shows a hopeful sign of the ro
i turn of the old-time sentiment of by
Igone days which for a time seemed
crushed out in the wild rush of com
nerclallsm which spread over the
i? land.

Government officials to display the
United States Flag on all Government
buildings, nnd tho peoplo of the
United States to display tho flag at
their homes or other suitable places
on tho second Sunday In May as a
pnblio expression of our lovo and rev
erence for the mothers of our country.
And Whereas, by the said joint Rcs
olution it is made tho duty of the
President to request the observation
J of the second Sunday in May as pro
j Tided for In the said joint Resolution;
Now, Therefore, I, Wooclrow Wfl
rj son, President of the United States
;J of America, by virtue of the authority
vested in mo by the said Joint Rcso
lution, do hereby direct tho Govern-
i W11 above, a proclamation by the
3 M President of the United States,
i added another day to the calen
j dar of our national holidays and
yone which has a tender significance
j and shows a hopeful sign of the ro
i turn of the old-time sentiment of by
Igone days which for a time seemed
crushed out in the wild rush of com
nerclallsm which spread over the
i? land.
f) T"
merit officials to display .tho United
States Flag on all Government build
ings, and do invito tho peoplo of the
United States to display tho flag at
their homes or other suitablo places
on tho second Sunday in May as a
public expression or our lovo and rev
erence for tho Mothers of our coun
try. In witness whereof I have set my
hand and caused tho Seal of tho
United States to bo hereunto affixed.
Done at the City of Washington, this
ninth day of May, in the year of our
Lord One Thousand Nino Hundred and
Fourteen, and the Independence of the
United States One Hundred and Thirty-Eight,
WOODROW WILSON.
By tho President:
William Jennings .Bryan,
Secretary of State."
(SEAL)
Older Tlian Christianity
Tho celebration of Mothers' Day,
while new to us as a feast day, Is In
history older than Christianity Itself,
for Mother-worship with its rites and
ceremonies dates back to tho days of
the pagans when Cybele, tho Groat
Mother of Gods, was idealized in
Greece two centuries or more before
tho coming of Christ. Later tho day
became known as tho festival of Hll
arla and was hold on the Ides of
March. As was tho custom of tho
day, offerings wore made at tho tem
ple." With tho advent of Christianity
the festival was changed, and although
It still Included many pagan customs,
It becamo a celebration" In honor of
Mother Church and was held on Mid
Lent Sunday, or tho fourth Sunday In
Lent On this day tho faithful came
to bring offerings to Mother Church.
Finally, tho day took tho name of
Mothering Sunday, and was sot aside
as-tho time when peoplo should pay
visits to their paronts, especially to
tholr mothers, also that they should
carry with them some cako or trinket.
"Going a-mothcrlng" soon becamo tho
fashion and a certain kind of cako
known as simncl cako was carried as
a gift to tho mothor. Horrick, tho
poet, In addressing one of tho char
actors of his poem on Mothering,
says:
"I'll to thee a slmnel bring
Gainst thou go a-mothering,
So that when sho blessos theo,
Half that blessing thou'lt give me."
This proves that even In tho early
days tho mothers' blosslng was highly
regarded.
In England tho slmnel cake3 woro
composed of a crust made of flno flour
and water with sufficient saffron to
give it a deop yellow color and the
interior filled with such ingredients
as Is used In plum puddings. They
aro boiled and brushed over with egg
and set away to harden. When they
are to bo used they must bo robaked
and softened. This, custom was In
vogue during tho seventeenth century
when every child who resided away
from homo was expected to carry a
slmnel to his or her mothor. Fre
quently tho cakes wero kept until
Easter -and sorved ns tho desert for
the dinner on that day.
Early Celebrations
Mothers' Day was first observed in

1908 In Philadelphia by Bevoral of
tho Sunday schoolB, and in 1909 about
two thousand people took part In tho
services. Seattle, Washington, how
over, has tho honor of being tho real
pioneer In a genuino Mothers' Day
celebration. This was In 1900 when
hundrods of peoplo gathered in tho
churches of that city on tho second
Sunday In May. They carried bou
quets and wreaths of flowers and at
the closo of sermons on "Mothor
Lovo" tho entire congregations hold
tholr flowors aloft whllo tho pastor
pronounced a blessing, and at the
closo of tho service tho flowers were
gathered together and placed on the
graves of mothers whoso relatives
wero not in tho city to perform this
loving service.
In 1910 tho Governor of tho State
of Washington set asldo tho eighth
of May ot that year as Mothers' Day
for that Stato, and over slnco that tlmo
tho proclamation of Mothers' Day has
been issued with tho samo regularity
as that of Thanksgiving. A request
is also added that each person wear
a whlto flower on tho day and that
special services should bo held in tho
churches.
Tho Stato of Oklahoma was the next
to fall in lino wltha Mothers' Day
proclamation, whon Governor Leo
Cruco in 1912 paid such a glowing
tribute to motherhood in his procla
mation to tho peoplo of that Stato:
"Each citizen, whether old or
young, rich or poor, happy or -sorrowful,
remember her whoso
lovo passeth human understand
ing, and remembering, manifest
to tho world your lovo nnd gratl
tudo by wearing a carnation In
honor of tho dearest of all moth
ers, and wearing It, think of her
and love her."
Slnco that tlmo many Slatos have
followed the example of these two.
Western States, and at present tho day
has takon-'H prdrrfihent plnfo among
our feast days. Sermons aro preached
on tho subject of motherhood in the
majority of our churches. Tho Sun
day schools have a Mothors Day ser
vice, and In tho afternoon many go
out to tho cemotories to cover tho
gravo of "man's best friend" with gar
lands of flowors.
Mothers' Pensions
Tho celebration of Mothers' Day
has brought about a stronger feeling
on tho subject of pensioning mothers,
and ono Is surprised to learn how
many States havo already adopted tho
pensioning system for mothors who
aro too poor to properly caro for their
chlldron. Whllo the plan is too now
to show vory many benefits to tho
mother and child tho sponsors of tho
bill In tho City of Chicago aro of the
opinion that a child can bo maintained
at homo choaper than It can in an in
stitution, and also that a child with
a homo is less likely to turn criminal
than tho ono brought up in an Insti
tution. Tho statistics of tho Stato Re
formatory at Elmlra in Now York
Stato provo tho above .to bo true In
that Stato at least, sixty per cent
of the Inmates having been brought
up In Institutions instead of homes.
"Home with Mother" is the aim for
the child by the charity workors of
the present day. "Assist the mother
financially," they say, "and sho will
caro for her child In such a manner
that Stato Reformatories will not bo
needed. Tho preservation of tho
home is worth all It cost3 a Common
wealth." Twonty-two States are al
ready In lino In this work: Arizona.
California, Idaho, Iowa, Illinois, Mary
land. Massachusetts, Michigan, Min
nesota. Missouri, Nebraska, Nevada,
New Hampshire, Now Jersey, New
York, Ohio, Oklahoma, Oregon, Penn
sylvania, South Dakota, Utah. Wash
ington and Wisconsin.
Mother Influence on Statesmen
Tho significance of Mothers' Day
should find an echo in every heart,
for It was tho mothors of our Statos-
Imen who Jn the early days put our
'Nation on a 'firm foundation "The
hand that rocks the cradlo Is the hand I
that rules tho world." It was tho
mother of Georgo Washington who,
by hor woman's intuition that ho was
mado for better things, saved him
from becoming a midshipman on a
British ship. It was the turning
point in tho life of tho Father of his
Country whon rather than causo his
mother sorrow ho roturnod his middy
uniform and said "Mothor I can never
go and cause you so much grief. I
will stay at homo." With Washing
ton In tho British Navy thero might
have been no Monmouth and no York
town. Tho character of Androw Jackson's
mother stands out in Amorlcan his
tory like a speck of blue in tho dark
sky of those early days in tho moun
tains. Her advice to her son Bhows
the wisdom of Polonlus and may well
bo treasured by tho man who desires
to succood. Jackson never forgot hor
words of advice and a short time be
fore his death he repeated her part
ing advice to a young man in whom
ho was interested.
Again In the life of Abraham Lin
coln wo find the Influence of his
mothor. When sho died away out
thero in tho Indiana wilderness so
far from civilization that her body
was consigned to tho ground without
a prayer, the boy determined that Bho
should not go unhonored, and throe
months later ho persuaded a parson
from Kentucky to proach a sermon
and conduct the services for tho dead
over her grave. In after years when
tho burdens of Stato and a dlsunitod
Nation caused him such travail of
soul his thoughts reverted to his
mother's teachings and he applied
them to his acts. Only a few days
before his death, In talking to a
friend, ho spoko of tho pioneer days
and the poverty he had endurod. "All
that I am or hope to bo," ho said, "I
owe to my angel mother."
Many persons will recall tho tender H
affection which existed between tho
lato President McKlnley and his
mother, and of his telling his asso- H
elates how much he owed to her Chris- H
tlan teachings of tho Golden Rule,
"Tho mothor's heart Is tho child's M
school room," wrote Henry Ward M
Beochor. "If you would reform the IH
world from Its errors and vices begin vH
by enlisting the mothers" is a quota- H
tlon far older than tho suffrage move- H
ment, but ono that was used In carry- fl
lng through a recent Mothers' Pension H
Bin. n
"All that I over accomplished In M
life," wroto Dwlght L. Moody, the i H
groat evangelist "I owe to my M
mother." "A kiss from my mother M
made "me a painter," is Benjamin jH
West's tribute to his mother. Even M
the great Napoleon bowed to the in- M
fluenco of tho maternal parent "Tho H
future of the child is always tho work H
of tho mother," he said. "Let France M
havo good mothers and sho will havo IB
ood sons." fl
Mother Love gfl
Hundreds of poems have been writ- H
ten on tho onduranco of mother love, H
and how when deserted and a failure H
In life the mother heart goes out to H
tho black sheep of tho family rather H
than to tho ones who have mado a H
success. Willis expresses theso sentl- H
ments in a happy fashion when no H
writes: H
"Youth fades, lovo droops, tho U
leaves of friendship fall; M
A mother's secret hope outlives H
them all." H
Long may Mothers' Day reign in our H
calendar of feasts, may tho Nation H
ever do honor to this saint among JM
women Hang out Old Glory In her j H
namo! J H

</text>
      </result>

	          <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/item/sn83045211/1916-06-29/ed-1/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>FOUNDER OF "MOTHERS' DAY"
THANKS AD MEN FOR CO-OPERATION
Miss Anna Jarvis Gives Ad
vertising Men Credit for
Plan
The founder of Mother's Day and tho
Mother's Day International Association
wishes to thank with nlncero appreciation
every member of the Associated Advertising
Clubs who has ever helped for Mother's
Day success.
Mother's Day success.
Mother's Day was first promoted by
Philadelphia papers, and through the co
operation of the press of this and other
countries has been mado an International
celebration. No movement of the century
has obtained so wonderful a hold on the
hearts of tho peoplo under such a multi
tude of dinicultleH and limitations In estab
lishing and promoting It. Tho press, how
ever, has been the one stanch and good
friend of Mother's Day since Its early days,
Mother's Day Is for the honor of the
home, especially Its motherhood, by older
people as well as children, and by the na
tion, that must look to the home as the
fountain head of that which Is good and
true.
The celebration always occurs the second
Sunday in May In homes and churches.
Schools, clubs, etc., celebrate during the
week preceding.
The Mother's Day badge la tho white
carnation, emblem .of the beauty, truth and
fidelity of mother love.
The slogan of Mother's Day Is, "In honor
of the best mother who ever lived, tho
mother of my heart"
As friends of this Mother's Day move
ment, which so distinctly honors your own
mothers, will you not help us to promote
In our way a worldwide, simultaneous celc-
MISS ANNA JARVIS
brntlon of Mother's Day, with the white
carnntlon as tho emblem to be worn, on the
second Sunday of May, and letters or acts
of affection to homes, etc., ns one of tho
simple, easy ways of celebrating?
ANNA JARVIS. Founder.
</text>
      </result>

<result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/item/sn95060583/1922-05-18/ed-1/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>MOTHER 0' MINE
It 1 were hanged on the highest hill.
Mother o' mine, O mother o mine!
1 know whose love would follow me still.
Mother o mine, O mother o' mine!
It I were drowned in the deepest sea.
Mother o mine, O mother o' mine!
I know whose tears would come down to
me.
Mother o' mine, O mother o' mine!
If I were cursed in body and soul,
Mother o mine, O mother o mine!
I know whose prayers would make me
whole.
Mother o' mine, O mother o' mine!
Rudyard Kipling.
By JOHN DICKINSON SHERMAN
OTHER'S Day should be
celebrated 365 days In
the year. There's no
need to argue about it.
Every man and woman
blessed with a good
mother knows it's true
and knows why it's true.
It doesn't take a very
old child to understand,
either.
But, since human nature is human
nature, every day isn't observed as
Mother's Day. There is all the more
reason, therefore, for observing the
second Sunday in May May 14, this
year with a real celebration. Some
one has tried to figure out a real cele
bration after this fashion for sons:
Wear a flower in mother's honor
a white one if mother is dead; a col
ored flower for a living mother.
Send mother a box of spring flowers.
Write her a letter a long one.
Give mother a whole day of your
time for that "good visit" she longs
for.
Send mother your picture, and snap
shots of your home, your children,
your work.
Tell mother, your plans and ambi
tions she made them possible.
Tell mother your smaller troubles
she wants to help you.
Thank mother for her care and her
teachings tell her how they have
helped you.
Don't forget that mother still likes
candy.
Mother was your first and truest
sweetheart don't forget to say "I
love you I"
For the daughters these things are
suggested
It's your chance to say "thank you"
to your best friend your mother.
Be sure to celebrate by wearing a
flower for mother: White for mothers
not living; colored flowers for mother
still with you.
Send mother some gay spring flow
ers, a brilliant bouquet or a thrifty
plant.
Make a dainty cap or a "dress-up"
gown or shirtwaist as a love gift to
mother.
If mother is far away, send her a
"special delivery letter" for her Sun
day treat.
Send mother the book you just en
Joyed reading.
Don't forget to send her pictures of
yourself, your friends and your good
times.
Tell mother your small joys and sor
rows and ask her advice It will be
good.
Ask mother to tell you about her
girlhood you'll both enjoy it.
Mother is a gin too. She likes pretty
things, love, laughter and compliments.
Give her some.
The spirit of this celebration is
right enough. The letter of it fails.
Nobody can tell you how to observe
Mother's Day.. You know. If she's a
red carnation mother make her happy.
If she's a white carnation mother, do
something that would make her happy
if she were a red carnation mother.
Nobody can draw up a celebration
schedule for Mother's Day. How can
one, when nobody can find adequate
words to write about Mother's Day?
Mother's Day is something new In
the way of holidays not like Christ
mas and Easter which are old, old
holidays. And It's new, compared with
the Fourth of July. In fact, It's just
about the newest holiday we have.
It was no longer ago than 1906 that
Miss Anne Jarvis of Philadelphia, hon
oring the memory of her own mother
on the anniversary of her death, con
ceived of a day of which everyone
should do reverence to his mother,
whether living or dead. The World's
Sunday School association adopted the
plan, and, in the next few years, an
nually designated one Sunday as
Mother's Day. The purposes of this
celebration, as stated by Dr. George
W. Bailey, then president of the asso
ciation, were:
"To recall the memories of the
mothers that are gone, and through
loving words and loving care to
brighten the lives of the mothers that
remain, and to help children, men and
women to a greater blessing in honor
ing their fathers and their mothers.
"To recall mother's prayers, moth
er's dying words, and the promises
made to mother by the big boy that
still mourns her, and to stop and think
a little of what she was in her life to
her family."
In 1908 Miss Jarvis founded an or
ganization now known as Mother's Day
International association.
The idea was taken up by the states.
In 1910 the governor of Washington
Issued a proclamation designating
May 8 of that year as "Mother's Day"
and urged It be celebrated by special
services and the wearing of a white
flower in honor of all mothers. In 1912
the governor of Oklahoma issued a
similar proclamation.
National recognition was given
Mother's Day by resolution of the
Sixty-third congress, approved by the
President of the United States on May
8, 1914, designating that the second
Sunday in May thereafter should gen
erally be known as "Mother's Day,"
and directing that it should be the
duty, of the President to request its ob
servance by Issuing a proclamation
calling upon the government officials
to display the United States flag on
all government buildings, and the peo
ple to display the flag at their homes
or other suitable places on this day,
"as a public expression of our love
and reverence for the mothers of our
country."
Originally the white carnation was
the flower worn in observance of the
day. Then, the public settled on white
carnations for mothers dead and ted
carnations for mothers living; then on
white flowers and colored flowers.
Now the tendency is to wear "mother's
favorite flower."
The great of the world have been
proud to pay tribute to mothers.
Unhappy is the man for whom his
own mother has not made all other
mothers venerable. Rlchter.
A man never sees all that his mother
has been to him till it's too late to
let her know that he sees it. W. D.
Howells.
If you would reform the world from
its errors and vices, begin by enlisting
the mothers. C. Simmons.
I think It must somewhere be writ
ten that the virtues of the mothers
shall be visited on their children, as
well as the sins of the fathers.
Charles Dickens.
The loving sacrifices of motherhood
must burn on the altar of undying
faith. If I could bequeath but one
priceless heritage to youth, it would
be the ability to know the full measure
of her love. Her Influence is the most
changeless thing in the fiber of a
man's character. It outweighs arts,
science, literature and philosophy, for
her faith and works are better than
all the wise man's knowledge. Sena
tor Lawrence T. Sherman.
Then there Is the Gold Star Mother
and the Mother in Time of War oh,
what's the use!
But they do say in France that in
the moment of his wounding the Brit
ish soldier thought first of his sweet
heart, the French soldier of his wife
and the. American soldier of his moth
er. Never mind who won the World
war; there's glory enough for all.
But history will record this fact:
America showed the world in this sol
dier who thought first ot his mother,
a new kind of fighting man:
He marched laughing to the front
Veterans pitied him as a mere youth.
Children loved him as one of them.
Women gave him smile for smile.
The enemy found him terrible a
fighting man who could not be stopped.
	</text>
      </result>

    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
